Alright, in this lesson, we'll be discussing the background task, uh,
the logic and code implementation.
First, why do we need to create this background task?
Because we're about to work on, um,
the OPIAS OPEX encoding,
we need to convert our recorded
PCM audio, right?
into the OPEZ format.
And this is a CPU-intensive task.
It involves a lot of computation.
We hand that over to the background task.
We'll directly pass it to this task.
Then, after the task is encoded, it will return the results to us.
That's how it works.
So, we need this background task.
The logic behind this background task,
is somewhat similar to what I covered in my previous IoT course,
if you've heard it before.
At that time, we were about to
throw all those functions into this Casla segment
in a way that wraps up the ending
and then register all the loop functions inside
into an array
and then, within the while loop
the while loop inside the 'made'
uniformly process this array
by iterating and running the array, and that's it
He doesn't care what's inside this array.
He just blindly runs it.
It's the same here as well.
Let's look at this; there's a producer and consumer concept here.
This kind of concept.
Let's look at this; these are the background tasks here.
This box here.
Inside this box are the background tasks.
The background tasks we created.
The background task has a consumer thread.
This consumer thread is essentially a while loop.
It's a loop that runs here.
How does it work?
It fetches from the queue.
The queue is processed each time, taking out items from it.
And then it clears the queue.
After fetching, um,
a lock needs to be added when fetching at that moment.
When retrieving
other threads might be adding to it, right?
That wouldn't be acceptable
So we need to lock when retrieving
After locking
once we've retrieved it
after retrieving everything
we immediately release the lock
After releasing the lock
This queue will do.
Others can proceed then.
So we'll synchronize here.
We've got this, um,
the function in the queue,
we just loop and execute it blindly, alright?
If there's a callback inside the execution,
it will trigger the callback.
So that's how it works.
So, who puts items into this queue?
Well, there are many existing producers first.
These are the producers.
These are the consumers.
The consumer is essentially consuming a message from this.
The function inside is for consumption, isn't it?
They take it out and use it.
Then it's gone, right?
Producers are responsible for putting items into the queue.
This also includes a function for submitting tasks.
It's equivalent to what we'll have in the backend tasks.
This class will contain a task submission method.
The task submission method is designed for producers.
Producers will call this task submission method.
To handle their time-consuming tasks.
The time-consuming functions.
Will be invoked and pushed to it.
It will then place them into the queue.
Of course, a lock will be added during the process.
Because it is synchronous, you see.
There could be multiple ones, right?
So a lock needs to be added when placing items.
Otherwise, when you place them,
you wouldn’t know how many we have placed, right?
So a lock is added here.
When submitting tasks,
it will handle the function tasks you submitted.
We place it into this queue.
Then it's added in.
After it runs.
It picks up the next one from this queue.
This process repeats continuously.
It works like this.
The logic is basically this.
Like this.
For instance, if the producer thread is a program coded in OPEX.
It keeps putting it in there
but this is one of its, um
the OPEX decoding program also gets placed in there
it runs here
it runs mindlessly
basically, it’s all about the CPU doing the calculations
anyway, the result of the computation is like this
as for the logic inside
we’ll be writing this part when the time comes
Let's talk about the logic
Applied logic can be written here.
This is the backend part
Our backend section
What we need to complete is the logic for this part
That is, we need to write a task submission function
We need to define a queue
Define this queue
Then write a task submission function
Then add a lock
It means adding a locking mechanism
We need to add a mutex lock
And then when we submit tasks
When others submit tasks
When I put them into the queue
I need to acquire the lock first
If I can't get it
That means this submitting thread
When submitting
When calling this
it gets blocked, right?
Then it waits for the lock to be released
you run it again
That's how it is
multithreading is quite multithreaded
This way, it's thread-safe
Then we submit this task
This is the function.
It encodes each program like OPA.
He submitted this task.
This can also be referred to as a function.
Because ultimately, what is obtained is a function.
After submitting this function,
it must ensure that it is thread-safe internally.
That means there are no resource contention issues within it.
For example, when you operate hardware.
That won't do.
If you operate the hardware,
it might lead to resource contention.
So, you need to implement a locking mechanism internally.
Here, you submit to me
is to ensure that this single instance,
is thread-safe,
there should be no contention.
Because I execute it blindly here,
I won't consider anything inside,
whether you need to add locks or not.
I don't want to worry about it.
Just run what you gave me, then.
That's the logic.
And, um,
this is an explanation of how the entire logic is implemented.
And the specific implementation video link is right here.
When you get to this point,
Tap here to download this video and watch it.
I'll also post the source code.
Alright, that's it for this lesson.